Giacomo Debidda

giacomodebidda.com giacomo@giacomodebidda.com GitHub / LinkedIn / Stack Overflow



Freelance full stack developer specialized in Node.js and Google Cloud Platform. I have been writing software professionally for almost ten years. Some of the things I did are: data analysis / visualizations in Python and JavaScript, web applications in TypeScript, Jibraries in Zig, performance audits for news and eCommerce websites.

Experience

Freelance full stack developer @ self-employed (2020-present): Developed applications in Node.js. Open sourced a few <u>libraries</u> for frontend (11ty), backend (Hapi.js), databases (SQLite, Firestore). Experimented with <u>Clojure</u> and <u>Zig</u>.

Software developer @ **Develer SrI** (2018-2020): Developed frontend architecture, UI components and API endpoints for a 3D configurator software (React, Redux, Three.js, Flask).

Software developer @ Moticon GmbH (2015-2017): Developed frontend components (D3.js) and backend logic (Python) for the company flagship product.

Education

Certifications: Associate Cloud Engineer, Google Cybersecurity Certificate.

Academia: Master in Clinical Engineering (Università di Firenze), MSc and BSc in

Biomedical Engineering (Università di Pisa).

Relevant Coursework: Data Analysis and Statistical Inference, Google Cloud Database Engineer Specialization, Machine Learning, Preparing for Google Cloud Certification: Cloud Data Engineer, Site Reliability Engineering: Measuring and Managing Reliability.

Skills

Frontend: 11ty, React, Svelte, D3.js, WebGL, SVG.

Backend: Next.js, Hapi.js, Fastify, Express, Cloudflare Workers.

Data: SQLite, Firestore, PostgreSQL, BigQuery, Apache Beam, Apache Airflow.

Cloud: GCP, Cloudflare, AWS, Fly.io, Scaleway, Cloudinary.

APIs: Stripe, HubSpot, Reddit.

Hobbies

I am very much into surf skating and inline skating. I try doing either one of the two at least 3 times a week. I also go to the gym and I have recently started boxing.